

# Sergei Shilko

Software Engineer







English, Russian, German, Polish, Ukrainian,











# **BACKGROUND**

#### **ABOUT**

Hi, I am Sergei Shilko, i graduated in 2010 MS Psychology with study on role of personal characteristics in a successful Software/IT career. Since first year in university i already worked for IT company and now i have more than 10 years of experience in Web/IT engineering. I managed work on multiple software projects ranging from small plugins and internal IT systems to build from scratch backend systems for high load. My expertise domains are Web, Mobile and APIs for backend applications. I like to solve technical and business problems with focus on client requirements and working closely with product teams.

# WORK EXPERIENCE

#### Head of Engineering, Tripod Technlogy GmbH

Jun, 2016 - Present

SRE & Cloud Architecture of backend APIs, IT, Operations, Concept. Reporting and liaising directly with CEO & external stakeholders

- Scaled, monitored and developed all backend infrastructure
- Migrated application services into containers (Docker)
- Experimented with K8S, Rancher, Swarm orchestration
- Built full CI/CD pipeline on AWS Pipeline inc. Blue/Green deployments and AutoScaling
- Promoted AWS Best Practices, AWS Well-Architected
- China and SEA connectivity improved, ICP/Hosting issues resolved
- Refactored, maintaned and upgraded application code and infrastructure
- Added more analytics, KPI & revenue, retention and engagement tracking
- Migrated from PHP 5.4 to 7.2, Ubuntu 12 to Debian 9, AWS EC2-Classic to VPC
- · Hired, onboarded and directly managed new dev members
- Enforced unit & integration testing, code review & code style policies

#### Senior FullStack Software Developer, Tripod Technlogy GmbH

Jun, 2013 - Jun, 2016 3 years

Mature backend solutions for audio/video (tele)communications software. Developing public API for mobile clients.

- Refactored of old inherited prototype codebase into working product, did first production release
- Celebrated first 50 users sign-up on GA dashboard and first promotions on iTunes
- Implemented json-rpc API for mobile app based on Adobe Flex and added support later for native iOS & Android app
- Deprecate legacy on-premise hosting and migration into AWS EC2-Classic
- Celebrated 2015 Most innovative app of the year (Apple iTunes)
- Implemented custom framework with open-source components
- Reduced API response times from >=2000ms to ~100ms
- Implemented critical app functionality: messenger, userfeed, email-reminders, search and more

### Lead Software Developer, Yangutu LLC

Nov, 2011 - Nov, 2012 **()** 1 year

Working on web based social network.

- Added API for supporting external 3rd party Game-platform add-on's
- Added AMF Flex/ActionScript API Server for import/export of data to mobile platform
- Added Facebook, Instagram, VK and other social networks integrations
- Extended import/export API's

# Contractor, Cygno Solutions LLC

Sep, 2011 - Nov, 2011 3 2 months

Short term freelance experience, integrating payment gateways and external API into existing project

- Added PayPal integration into existing project
- Added DineroMail (South America Payment platform) integration into existing project

# PHP Developer, eHarmony, Inc

Aug, 2008 - Sep, 2011 3 years 1 month

eHarmony Reporting and Management Tools for Risk Management team.

- Developed CMS/RMS Internal service from specification to manage and automate risks and fraud detection
- Working with sensitive client payment information
- Extended CMS/RMS service with flexible and configurable multi-role authentication system for different regions
- Added support for localization and translation of CMS/RMS
- Added analytics and audit tools for tracking and optimizing team (users or the CMS/RMS) performance
- Received feedback: UI/UX, bugs, new features suggestions and implemented

# Software Developer, IponWeb

Aug, 2007 - Sep, 2011 **(**) 4 years 1 month

SOAP/Rest API for real-time AD Exchange platform (formerly RightMedia.com)

- Worked on SOAP-API for high-load real-time advertising platform at scale
- Heavily extended and rewrote existing funtional test coverage, integrational e2e testing
- Covered many new edge cases in tests which lead to fixes in critical API parts

# Contractor, Yahoo!

May, 2008 - Mar, 2009 **③** 10 months

Maintaining RightMedia AD Exchange API migration after Yahoo! purchase

Refactoring tests, code and documentation, working with remote Yahoo developers team

# Intern, Developer, Sinytech LLC

Dec, 2005 - Aug, 2007 **①** 1 year 8 months

E-commerce websites for multiple clients/brands

- · Learned CGI, HTML, CSS Web and IT
- Worked on custom CMS
- Integrated VeriSign payment processor
- Extended existing CMS codebase (MVC) with new functionality
- Implemented and released in production multiple e-commerce projects based on common CMS/framework



```
FrontEnd Web Development
          CSS Javascript jQuery
                                  SEO
   HTML
   Backend JS Development
   NodeJS PhantomJS NightmareScript
   BackEnd Web Development
   MySQL 5.5 - 5.7 MongoDB
                                     SphinxSearch
                                                   ManticoreSearch
                                                                    Docker
                                                                                            Adobe AMF
                                                                             Docker Swarm
   PHP ZendFramework 1 | Custom PHP Frameworks / MVC | PHP 5.5 - 7.2 | Beanstalkd | RabbitMQ | Gearman
                           Puppet
                                    Nginx
                                          Git JSON-RPC
                                                          PHPUnit
                                                                    Curl Grep Bash Sysctl/Systemd
   AMQP & MQTT
                  Vagrant
   PHPStorm
                   Emacs
                            SublimeText
              Vim
  AWS Cloud
   EC2
         ELB
              Lambda
                           RDS ElastiCache
                                              VPC
                                                    CloudFront
                                                               Route 53
                                                                          API Gateway
                                                                                        CodeCommit
                                                                                                     CodeBuild
   CodeDeploy
                CodePipeline
                             CloudWatch
                                          IAM
                                                ECR
                                                     Cognito
                                                               Certificate Manager
                                                                                   WAF & Shield
   Mobile Hub | PinPoint | WorkMail
  Other
           SVN, Mercurial
                          NewRelic
                                     Debian
                                             Alpine Linux
                                                          Amazon Linux
                                                                        Arch Linux
                                                                                    Ubuntu
                                                                                             Gentoo Mac OS
   Facebook API | Apple APNS | Google FCM | Alipay Payments | Baidu PN | Google & iTunes Payments
                                     SparkPost, Mandrill
   Stripe, Paypal Payments
                           OpenTOK
                                                         Kubernetes
EDUCATION
 Psychology, Personal characteristics of successful Software Engineers, Grodnenski Dzjaržauny Universitet imja Janki
 Kupaly
 Sep, 2005 - Sep, 2010
 Cognitive psychology
                      Psychodiagnostics | Experimental psychology
 Electrical engineering, High voltage electrical relays and automation controls, GGPEK Technical College
 Sep, 2003 - Sep, 2005
 High voltage engineering
 Electrical engineering, , Community College
 Sep, 2000 - Sep, 2003
 AWARDS
 Yearly city college IT competition 1st place
 Awarded on: Jan 01, 2003
 Local city contest across different education institutions
 Yearly country IT competition 3rd place
 Awarded on: Jan 01, 2005
 Country contest across all education institutions from all regions
 AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate (SAA) 3GV5K7KKC14Q17W1
 Awarded on: Dec 13, 2018
INTERESTS
 Conferences
 Belin - AWS Summit 2014 | Belin - AWS Summit 2015 | Belin - AWS Summit 2016 | Berlin - AWS Summit 2017
 KubeCon + CloudNativeCon 2018 | Berlin - AWS Summit 2019 | KubeCon + CloudNativeCon 2019
 Podcasts and Forums
                      Radio-T IXBT Habr
 Golang - Golangshow
 Traveling
 Greece Spain Georgia Germany Poland Greek islands Lithuania Russia Egypt
 PC Geek
                               ZX Spectrum
                                                    LAN & Wireless
 Modding
                 Raspberry Pi
                                             Retro
 Reading
 Management Agile Scrum Sci-Fi Fantasy Horror Clean Code TDD Architecting for the Cloud Best practices
                   IT novels
                             Marketing and selling high-tech products | Scalable and maintainable systems
             Managing successful projects | Building teams | Software architect wisdom | Isaac Asimov
                                                                                                  Robert Heinlein
 George Orwell Terry Goodkind Alan Kuper Tom DeMarco
 eSports
         International
                       Competitive teams
                                          Broadcasting
```

**SKILLS** 



REFERENCES

Arnd Aschentrup / CEO Tripod Technology GmbH